[
    {
        "question": "Where was the 85th All India Presiding Officers Conference 2025 held?",
        "options": [
            "Lucknow  ",
            "Guwahati  ",
            "New Delhi  ",
            "Patna "
        ],
        "answer": "Patna ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Diamond Imprest Authorisation (DI",
        "options": [
            "Scheme, ",
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Scheme, ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The historical Ratnagiri site, which was in the news recently, is located in which state?",
        "options": [
            "Andhra Pradesh ",
            "Tamil Nadu ",
            "Bihar ",
            "Odisha "
        ],
        "answer": "Odisha ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been elected as the President of the Institute of Company Secretaries of India (ICSI) for 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Pawan G Chandak ",
            "Dhananjay Shukla ",
            "Nikesh Arora ",
            "Jay Chaudhry "
        ],
        "answer": "Dhananjay Shukla ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been elected as the Vice-President of the Institute of Company Secretaries of India (ICSI) for 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Sanjay Mehrotra ",
            "Jayshree Ullal ",
            "Rajeev Suri ",
            "Pawan G Chandak "
        ],
        "answer": "Pawan G Chandak ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Donald Trump has ordered the withdrawal of the United States of America from which international Organisation?",
        "options": [
            "World Trade Organization ",
            "World Health Organisation ",
            "International Labour Organization ",
            "United Nations Industrial Development Organization "
        ],
        "answer": "World Health Organisation ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Donald Trump has ordered the withdrawal of the United States of America from which international Treaty?",
        "options": [
            "Kyoto Protocol ",
            "Basel Convention ",
            "Ramsar Convention ",
            "Paris Agreement "
        ],
        "answer": "Paris Agreement ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "For how many days the Donald Trump government in the United States has halted foreign aid to foreign governments/organisations?",
        "options": [
            "75 days ",
            "45 days ",
            "90 days ",
            "60 days "
        ],
        "answer": "90 days ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the 3rd National Mining Ministers Conference, which state won the award for securing the first position for outstanding contribution in conducting the highest number of auctions in 2023-24?",
        "options": [
            "Rajasthan   ",
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Maharashtra ",
            "Odisha "
        ],
        "answer": "Rajasthan   ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "With whom has the Defense Ministry recently signed an agreement for Bridge Laying Tank?",
        "options": [
            "Heavy Vehicles Factory ",
            "Lockheed Martin ",
            "Hindustan Aeronautics ",
            "L&T "
        ],
        "answer": "Heavy Vehicles Factory ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Maharashtra signed MoUs worth how much at the World Economic Forum 2025 in Davos?",
        "options": [
            "\u20b94 lakh crore ",
            "\u20b95.5 lakh crore ",
            "\u20b96.25 lakh crore ",
            "\u20b97 lakh crore "
        ],
        "answer": "\u20b96.25 lakh crore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will the first International Olympic Research Conference be held?",
        "options": [
            "Bhopal ",
            "Jaipur ",
            "New Delhi ",
            "Gandhinagar "
        ],
        "answer": "Gandhinagar ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is India\u2019s current rank as a coffee producer globally?",
        "options": [
            "6th ",
            "7th ",
            "8th ",
            "9th "
        ],
        "answer": "7th ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country completed the world\u2019s longest expressway tunnel?",
        "options": [
            "Japan ",
            "South Korea ",
            "India ",
            "China "
        ],
        "answer": "China ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which platform has partnered with DPIIT to provide skilled manpower to startups?",
        "options": [
            "Bhaskar ",
            "AngelList ",
            "Apna ",
            "Naukri "
        ],
        "answer": "Apna ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum support price for raw jute announced by the government of India for the 2025-26 agricultural season?",
        "options": [
            "Rs 5350 per quintal   ",
            "Rs 6220 per quintal ",
            "Rs 4780 per quintal ",
            "Rs 5650 per quintal "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 5650 per quintal ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sub committee of the Union Cabinet approves the minimum support price for crops?",
        "options": [
            "Commission for Agricultural Costs and Prices ",
            "Department of Agriculture ",
            "Cabinet committee on Economic Affairs ",
            "Department of Economics and revenue "
        ],
        "answer": "Cabinet committee on Economic Affairs ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of India\u2019s first AI-powered credit card expert introduced by CheQ?",
        "options": [
            "Wisor ",
            "QPro ",
            "CardGenie ",
            "CheQuick "
        ],
        "answer": "Wisor ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "By which year has Piyush Goyal set a target to achieve 10,000 GI tags?",
        "options": [
            "2025 ",
            "2027 ",
            "2029 ",
            "2030 "
        ],
        "answer": "2030 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the men\u2019s singles title of the 2025 India Open Badminton Tournament?",
        "options": [
            "Viktor Axelsen ",
            "Lee Cheuk Yiu ",
            "Kim Won-ho ",
            "Seo Seung-jae "
        ],
        "answer": "Viktor Axelsen ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the women\u2019s singles title of the 2025 India Open Badminton Tournament?",
        "options": [
            "An Se-young ",
            "Pornpawee Chochuwong ",
            "Arisa Igarashi ",
            "Ayaka Sakuramoto "
        ],
        "answer": "An Se-young ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the rank of India in the Global Firepower Index 2025?",
        "options": [
            "5th ",
            "4th ",
            "3rd ",
            "2nd "
        ],
        "answer": "4th ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country\u2019s military was ranked as the most powerful in the world by the Global Firepower Index 2025?",
        "options": [
            "USA ",
            "Russia  ",
            "China ",
            "India "
        ],
        "answer": "USA ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was ranked at the bottom of the Global Firepower Index 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Pakistan  ",
            "Afghanistan  ",
            "Bhutan  ",
            "Sri Lanka "
        ],
        "answer": "Bhutan  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country will host the Chess World Cup 2025?",
        "options": [
            "India ",
            "Germany ",
            "USA ",
            "Norway "
        ],
        "answer": "India ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has recently become India's top chess player?",
        "options": [
            "Arjun Erigaisi ",
            "Parimarjan Negi ",
            "D Gukesh ",
            "Vidit Gujrathi "
        ],
        "answer": "D Gukesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which institution has recently released the \u201cDependency and Depopulation: Confronting the Consequences of New Demographic Reality\u201d report?",
        "options": [
            "World Health Organization ",
            "International Atomic Energy Agency ",
            "International Labour Organization ",
            "World Data Lab  "
        ],
        "answer": "World Data Lab  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the World Data Lab recent report, India will become the second largest global consumption economy on the purchasing power parity basis by which year?",
        "options": [
            "2030 ",
            "2040 ",
            "2050 ",
            "2070 "
        ],
        "answer": "2050 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which scheme of the government of India completed 10 years on 22 January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Pradhan Mantri E-Shram Yojana ",
            "Pradhan Mantri Kisan Maandhan Yojana ",
            "Pradhan Mantri Street Vendor Atmanirbhar Nidhi ",
            "Beti Bachao Beti Padhao "
        ],
        "answer": "Beti Bachao Beti Padhao ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the share of the state government in the funding of the Beti Bachao Beti Padhao Scheme?",
        "options": [
            "50% ",
            "60% ",
            "70% ",
            "100% "
        ],
        "answer": "100% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Beti Bachao, Beti Padhao (BBBP) scheme was launched to control which of the following declining options?",
        "options": [
            "Adult Sex Ratio ",
            "Child Sex Ratio ",
            "Education level in females ",
            "Health issues in female child "
        ],
        "answer": "Child Sex Ratio ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prabowo Subianto, the chief guest of Republic Day 2025, is the President of which country?",
        "options": [
            "Sri Lanka ",
            "Malaysia ",
            "Singapore ",
            "Indonesia "
        ],
        "answer": "Indonesia ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was sworn-in as the Chief Justice of Delhi High Court?",
        "options": [
            "Justice Devendra Kumar Upadhyay ",
            "Justice Alok Aradhe ",
            "Justice Ajay Kumar Sinha ",
            "Justice Deepak Mishra "
        ],
        "answer": "Justice Devendra Kumar Upadhyay ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mount Ibu is an active volcano located in which country?",
        "options": [
            "Chile ",
            "Japan ",
            "Ecuador ",
            "Indonesia "
        ],
        "answer": "Indonesia ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]